Kyle my name is Andrew chancellors and
this is my second video about right
JS in this video we will build on the
basics recovered in the first video
if you're looking for an introduction I
would recommend you start there
we'll cover how do you try it building
now and then
to run code as soon as the tag has been
mounted how to pass a function
an expression to give it access to coat
on our page
how to use Ryan's built-in support for
looping through data and a tank
custom events using the observable API
provided by Ryan
and finally will combine these
techniques to grab some Jason data
pass it into the tag and display the
data by looping through
like last time I've created directory
for the files to work with in this video
I have a terminal window open a basic
HTML file
and chrome open so we can look at the
results as we make changes
to get started will create the root
level tag that these examples will be
based on
the contact list ac well defined as an
attack file
will make the river file are tagged they
will give it some static content to
start with
so we can be sure everything is working
as expected all reference the tag on our
HTML
and at a call to write that now
our scripts tank and will fire up our
compiler
using the watch option so to update our
tags automatically as we make changes
and just like in the last video
will use the HTTP server node module to
run our app
and now it take a look at our page to
make sure everything is working
and will see their page loads up in our
static content from our tag is displayed
when i'm creating a new tag I we like to
do a quick sanity check like this to
make sure I haven't missed something
basic
that way if I make a mistake in my tag
doesn't now properly
at least I can eliminate the initial
setup is the cause my prop
high-tech file setup and loading
properly on the page so it's time to
take a look at the mountain
week alright that now and write finishes
manning the tag
the mountain aspired and art I can
respond to this with the handler
latter handler code in the script for
attack
in this case we're just going to lock
something out to the console so we can
see that the event handler was fired
might switch to the browser
open a developer tools we can see our
Console output
when I refresh the page and checked
consular put
will see that the mount event handler
code is executed
in the introductory video we saw how we
can pass
data into our tags using expressions we
can also pass functions into expressions
allowing us to give our tags call backs
let's go over how to do that
first for the final function on our page
my am just going to call a function tag
call back
and just like we did with the man event
we're going to use our console that
large us to see that it runs
to get this call at passing or tag we
can pass it in just like any other
argument
will call a call back
book has been a member function
announced that being passed in or tag
we can call their function from within
our tack so pronounces can add that
right at the top of our script
and we call it
call back in the attic that we pass that
amount method
and we can refresh your browser
and will see that the call that was
executed
and then than now event was fired so we
can see that it runs
let's just recap what's happening we had
a tag
and our tag set to function as a
property offers options object
in the pager Rican soon the tag with the
find our own function
and that function can have any logic we
need an A we passed that function
reference to the tag
attack and then run our custom object
through the function reference
in this example were just calling the
call back immediately
we can save that reference in users part
logic in a button's onclick handler
or some other event pass control back to
our application now we can make tags to
stay focused on the view
and can be reused more readily by
providing custom object where make sense
will revisit events in call back shortly
but for now
let's take a look at how we can Luther
said to data with right to get started
will set up an object that has an array
of objects as one of its properties
now it's past this data to our tag in
Mount method
more pass our peeps variable into
people property on the options object
now that that that has been passing or
tag
but look at how easy it is to Luther
using rights building
each attribute will display your
contacts in and unordered list
so it at that for each person in our ray
we're gonna want to add a new list item
to our list we can do that easily using
right
each attribute the each attribute
accepts an expression
in the format variable in collection so
in our case thoroughly p
in upstart people there's a create a new
instance at the El I element
for each item in our list and then we
can access the individualist item
using that he very well we declared in
our each attribute
and with that code written
let's take a look at the results as we
can see looking at pretty simple in
right now it's combined some of these
concepts
and make car tag a little bit more
useful we're gonna need to make some
changes
the first one is we're going to take a
call back and we're gonna move there
into the mound event handler so that we
know it doesn't get called
until the mountain and then is fired up
but they're quick sanity check in the
browser to make sure we didn't break
anything
and we can see
both items fire you also see that the
order changed
now that we know that works we're gonna
make some changes her call back function
so there's a little more use for
actually does something for this we're
gonna grass and Jason data
using an XML HTTP request for the
example
we're going to use data in NJ some file
in our directory structure
but this can be easily be replaced with
a call to arrest service for something a
little more useful
so its creator Jason data I'm gonna go
back to my html
and I'm gonna grab as this array of
people
forget to add a new file Unicode people
that Jason
you
I'll just add that in there because the
Jason file
who's gonna wrap the property names in
quotes as well
now that we have that
but at our XML HTTP request
you so create a variable called request
never be a new
XML HTTP request I'm gonna call
request open method and we're gonna pass
it get
as our HTTP verb and we're gonna pass it
a path to our file
just call people chase on
me want this to be a synchronous
and now add a handler for the request
unload event
am here with this check the status over
request
as long as we get a £200 response for
good
10 we have data
and we're gonna parse the Jason to grab
the response text
and put it into a variable called data
and we will come back to this in a
moment
we have to get the data
into the attack and of course in order
to get
any this to work we need to call request
that
sent so all this is gonna happen inside
ever call back
which is going to be called from inside
our tag when the mail
event fires but we still have to deal
with getting the data from
a call back in the page back into the
tag
so that we can use the data and look
through it right has a built-in
observable API which makes it easy to
trigger and respond to customer events
so we can leverage that to get data into
attack
in order to make sure we can trigger a
custom event in our tag from a call back
function
we're going to pass the tag instance to
it as an argument when we call it so
back in our tags JavaScript we call
are passing call back function we're
gonna pass a reference to this
and then back in our page
per call back is going to accept them
the argument as a reference to the tech
send a red tag is automatically
observable
just having that reference to the tag is
enough to allow us to call the trigger
method to comes with rights observable
API once our data is loaded
we're going to trigger a customer that
are tagged and pass our data as an
argument
so will call the tag
that trigger and this event name is one
we make up
so in caller that whatever seems
appropriate and the second argument for
trigger
is the data we're gonna pass in to our
event
something a reference data track people
and people is coming from
the name at the array in our Jason
object
and now that we're triggering that event
we need to go into a tag
and add a handler for we can add a
handler to our customer event just like
we did for the mount event
will start by calling this dot on
and then the name a bourbon which we
call data
underscore loaded and it's going to take
a call back
which will accept that passed in data as
an argument
and in the event handler
we're gonna sign are passed in keeps
value to our options
dot people art Agosto relying on the
static data that we passed into riot
that now
we originally started this example so
let's go back to the HTML page to remove
that
so we can see if our new code is
actually grabbing are Jason data and
putting it into attack
if we look in the
again we'll see that there are no people
as color tank file is responding to the
events
it's firing them an event is calling our
call back we can see from our
console are the call back is executing
our dad is being passed in
we have one important update to make and
that is a call to this
that update this is what tells Ryan
to re render and update values and the
TAC so when I refresh the page again
her tag will load a caller call back
call back a grabber Jason Dufner
once that's been done it'll fire of our
custom event
that one turn call update but they will
render the tag and we'll see our content
rendered to the page now just to see how
r tag will behave
fr service there was providing our data
took 'em
moment to respond let's add a setTimeout
around our XML HTTP requests and method
just to simulate that's a hard tackle
behave so this time out
will wait 2 seconds then call the
function
which one turn call request Arts & and
that will simulate
a slow loading time from our service and
jerry have the tag will behave
and we'll see that are static having
loads up
and then where and that time at is done
if finishes loading the Jays on data and
populates the page
if we waited for data torrent or page
and then down in the tag does so that we
could pass the data into that
now method than the entire thing would
have been lately when they've seen the
contacts header show up first
in this case maybe that's not a big deal
but if you have a tag
that encapsulates a larger application
you know what these things to happen
independently
but say for example we had a form that
could add additional names
and a pen them to the existing last
we can set this up so that the form is
active and we can do things locally
well it's going out to the service and
grabbing the existing data for us and it
had mergers list together
when we get a response I hope you found
this video helpful
thanks for watching and please feel free
to leave feedback